I will show you two ways to prepare a woman's pelvis,
to rebalance a pelvis and work on a birth axis.
It's exactly the same for the uterine or prostatic plane,
except that there is one thing that a man does not have: he does not have to give birth.
A man does not carry a child.
Here you have a tubercle, which we call the tubercle of the third adductor.
I take both tubercles here, and from there I have an important axis.
I can already determine...
the space, how it is situated, whether it is too far this way, or if it is like this. I place myself in the knot,
in the space, and it is the space that guides me, because I have a whole
axis here that is not
related to the midline. So the whole side here is slightly
depressed and too short,
so I have an imbalance here. So what I do here is I place myself in biodynamics with respect
to here. And to balance this, I position myself here and I hold the pelvis of the woman here.
And then the other here like this and here and there I support the whole
pelvis but at the same time I have
the axis in front of me here and I will let this biodynamics guide me as I relate
to
my central line and I take a point of support that is here; I create a triangle, I work
with a triangle, a little bit here like this, and I
position myself like this with a support.
Not quite on the ischiums, here.
Trochanter, right here.
When I have this awareness, I will let the pelvis itself reposition
relative to the point of support I have.
If I can’t do it this way, I will take another point.
So, I start from here.
Now, I have a tool.
Okay, this is my story.
You see, I can already determine.
I have the birth axis, right.
You see?
It’s an important axis, okay?
It needs to be free.
If I...
If I don’t have that, I take the pelvis here.
I will see how it positions, if it works.
If I haven’t corrected it yet, I go behind, on the ischium.
I go back here, I take the ischium.
You release, same side here.
I place my support here, she stays pretty upright.
And I let the whole process unfold by itself.
In any case, already a good point of support with my hands.
And I let the body work to rebalance the pelvic issues.
This is a technique that works.
on decongestions, on rebalancing, because if you are well-centered,
the vascular system releases, and the decongestions resolve themselves.
When you have a pregnant woman, first of all, it’s not always easy to lay her on her back.
If people have severe back pain, sometimes it’s best not to lay them down,
because when they sit up, they might undo all your work.
I let the space and primary breathing work.
I check every time I’m with a pregnancy, I verify the birth axis.
Are the feet free?
Is the axis
of birth aligned? And then I will look
here if necessary.
And if needed, I will position myself behind and let
the body rebalance. In fact,
it’s the space around that will rebalance.
And I always recheck at the end.
I need to have this feeling
that it’s... There is one thing that is
really fundamental to understand, and that is the child
when it is going to come out and make its
birth movement is guided
by the fascias of the pelvis.
If your pelvis is a bit unbalanced,
it may get stuck or blocked.